Xiao (Brandon) Han

Desk 01, 01BB01, University of Surrey, Guildford, Surrey, GU2 7XH, United Kingdom

□ (+44) 07529989025 | 🔀 xiao.han@surrey.ac.uk | 🌴 brandonhan.uk | 🖸 GitHub | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🎓 GoogleScholar

Research Interests

I am broadly interested in the field of Deep Learning. My current research interest lies in the intersection between Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing (*i.e.*, vision-language). My research goal is to build multi-modal AI systems that can be used in real-world applications (*e.g.*, e-commerce platform). My expertise includes but is not limited to vision-language pre-training and (parameter-efficient) adaptation, many vision-language tasks (*e.g.*, cross-modal retrieval, text-guided image retrieval, image captioning, text-based/guided image generation/editing), and some specific tasks (*e.g.*, person ReID).

Education

University of Surrey Guildford, UK

Рн.D. StudentJan. 2021 - Present (Jan. 2024)

- Major in Vision and Signal Processing at Centre for Vision, Speech and Signal Processing (CVSSP)
- Supervisors: Prof. Tao Xiang (principal) and Prof. Yi-Zhe Song
- Fully funded by University of Surrey FEPS/iFlyTek Ph.D. Scholarship
- Thesis Title (tentative): Fine-Grained Multimodal Deep Learning

Zhejiang UniversityHangzhou, ChinaBACHELOR OF ENGINEERINGSep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

- Major in Information Engineering at College of Information Science and Electronic Engineering (ISEE)
- Cumulative GPA: 3.92 / 4.00 (88.13 / 100), Third-year GPA: 3.94 / 4.00 (89.46 / 100)
- Thesis Title: Deep Learning-Based Features Prediction for Mass Spectrometry of Protein

Non-Degree Academic Experiences:

| Visiting student with Dr. Li Zhang at ZVG, Fudan University | Shanghai, China |
|--|---|
| Research assistant with Dr. Changbin Yu at AiR, Westlake University | Hangzhou, China |
| Visiting student with Prof. L. Jay Guo at EECS, University of Michigan | Ann Arbor, MI, USA |
| Exchange student with iESR program at University of Notre Dame | South Bend, IN, USA |
| | Research assistant with Dr. Changbin Yu at AiR, Westlake University Visiting student with Prof. L. Jay Guo at EECS, University of Michigan |

Work Experiences

Noah's Ark Lab

London, UK

RESEARCH INTERN (PT)

Dec. 2022 - Present

• Mentor: Jiankang Deng

• Project: Image Generation/Editing via Diffusion Models

PixelShift.AIShanghai, ChinaComputer Vision Algorithm Intern (FT)May 2020 - Sep. 2020

Mentors: Zhiming Ma and Meng Zhang

• Project: Immersive AR application (Google MediaPipe) and deployment of generative models (TFLite)

————— Publications

Conference -

Controllable Person Image Synthesis with Pose-Constrained Latent Diffusion

Xiao Han, Jiankang Deng, Xiatian Zhu, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

FAME-Vil: Multi-Tasking Vision-Language Model for Heterogeneous Fashion Tasks

Xiao Han, Xiatian Zhu, Licheng Yu, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

FashionViL: Fashion-Focused Vision-and-Language Representation Learning

Xiao Han, Licheng Yu, Xiatian Zhu, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

UIGR: Unified Interactive Garment Retrieval

Xiao Han, Sen He, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

ECCV 2022

Under Review

Oct. 2023

CVPR 2023

Jun. 2023

Oct. 2022

CVPRW 2022

Jun. 2022

0 0111. 202

eBayChallenge: A modularized codebase for large-scale product retrieval (based on PyTorch Lightning and Hydra)

- https://github.com/01BB01/eBayChallenge
- Implementation of our solution for eBay eProduct Visual Search Challenge FGVC9 (CVPR2022)

FashionViL: A codebase for fashion-related vision-and-language research (based on Meta AI MMF)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/mmf
- Implementation and extension of our paper FashionVil: Fashion-Focused Vision-and-Language Representation Learning

CompFashion: A modularized codebase for text-guided image retrieval (based on vanilla PyTorch)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/CompFashion
- Implementation and extension of our paper UIGR: Unified Interactive Garment Retrieval

TextReID: A modularized codebase for text-based person search (based on vanilla PyTorch)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/TextReID
- Implementation and extension of our paper Text-Based Person Search with Limited Data

| | Honors & Awards | |
|-----------|--|----------------------------------|
| 2022 | 2 nd Place, eBay eProduct Visual Search Challenge - FGVC9 (CVPR2022) | eBay, USA |
| 2021-2024 | Faculty of Engineering and Physical Sciences/iFlytek Scholarship | University of Surrey/iFlytek, UK |
| 2019 | Chunzhen International Exchange Scholarship | Zhejiang University, China |
| 2017-2019 | 3 rd Prize, Academic & Outstanding Student Scholarship | Zhejiang University, China |
| 2018 | Yongping Scholarship | Zhejiang University, China |
| 2018 | 3 rd Prize, National Talent Training Base Scholarship | Zhejiang University, China |
| 2018 | Honorable Mention Prize, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM) | COMAP, USA |
| 2017 | 3 rd Prize, Physics Innovation Competition in Zhejiang Province (Theory Part) | Zhejiang Physical Society, China |

Services

Teaching assistant / Demonstrator at University of Surrey

- EEEM071 (2023 Spring) Advanced Topics in Computer Vision and Deep Learning (under Prof. Yi-Zhe Song and Dr. Xiatian Zhu)
- Responsible for the final coursework design (Vehicle ReID) and lab tutorial preparation
- Responsible for demonstrating in lab sessions with 145+ PG/T students with mixed backgrounds
- Responsible for marking the experimental reports and examination papers

Project tutor at University of Surrey

- EEEM004 (2023 Spring) 60 Credit Standard Project (under Dr. Xiatian Zhu)
- Responsible for guiding PG/T final projects "Zero-/Few-shot learning with language supervision"

Conference reviewer

- 6th CVPR Workshop on Computer Vision for Fashion, Art, and Design (CVFAD) 2023
- International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023
- IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023
- AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2022
- ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACM MM) 2022
- IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME) 2022

Journal reviewer

• IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)

Skills

Programming Languages Python, C/C++, MATLAB, ŁTĘX, Verilog, JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML/CSS

Frameworks and Tools PyTorch, PyTorch Lightning, TensorFlow, Git, Docker, W&B

Codebases Meta Al MMF, HuggingFace Pipeline (e.g., Transformers/Diffusers), Google MediaPipe, timm

Languages 普通话 Mandarin (native), English (fluent), 한국어 Korean (beginner)

References

Will be provided upon request